An Inventory of the Thomas Sgovio papers, 1938-2008
Hoover Institution Archives
Thomas Sgovio papers
1938-2008
87038
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 5 framed paintings, digital files (4.2 linear feet)
Memoir, relating to imprisonment in Soviet forced labor camps; photocopies of Soviet arrest records and summaries of judicial proceedings, and of United States Federal Bureau of Investigation reports on interviews after repatriation; and 44 original paintings and drawings depicting living and working conditions in Soviet forced labor camps.
Sgovio, Thomas.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American artist; prisoner in Soviet forced labor camps, Kolyma and Krasnoyarsk regions, 1938-1954.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoir, relating to imprisonment in Soviet forced labor camps; photocopies of Soviet arrest records and summaries of judicial proceedings, and of United States Federal Bureau of Investigation reports on interviews after repatriation; and 44 original paintings and drawings depicting living and working conditions in Soviet forced labor camps.
Drawings.; Forced labor--Soviet Union.; Paintings.; Soviet Union--Pictorial works.
- Paintings and drawings depicting living and working conditions in Soviet forced labor camps (Box 1)
- Memoir relating to a return visit to the Kolyma forced labor camps in Russia in, 1995 (Box 2)
- Photocopies of arrest records and summaries of judicial proceedings, 1938-1996 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  In Russian with English translations
- Of the Russian Siberian Paintings by Thomas Sgovio, narrated by Grace Deitch Boogay DVD (Box 2)
- Celebration of the Century: Parade of Vehicles, on GM's 100th Birthday and the Tonawanda Engine's 70th anniversary DVD, 2008 September 12 (Box 2)
- Photocopies of United States Federal Bureau of Investigation memoranda, reports, and interview summaries relating to experiences of Thomas Sgovio in the Soviet Union, 1960-1970 (Box 3)
- Framed painting, "Slave Laborer: Kolyma Gold Fields" (Box 4)
- Framed painting, "Frost Bite" (Box 5)
- Framed painting of Kolyma prisoners with barbed wire (Item Art Rack)
- Framed painting of Kolyma prisoner (Item Art Rack)
- Framed painting, Strip Mining: Winter Work, Kolyma scene (Item Art Rack)
- Framed painting, Ballanda (Item Art Rack)
- Framed painting, Somewhere in the Frozen Archipelago (Item Art Rack)
- Scrapbook, circa 1910-1997 (File Reading room workstation)
  Contains certificate issued by military tribunal, District of Moscow; photographs and photocopies of photographs (family, street scenes, artwork); newspaper clippings and photocopies of clippings; and other printed matter. Some photos have captions in English, Italian, or Russian. (106 digital files)